Nordic Track is one of the leaders in
cardio equipment and while their
products tend to cost an arm and a leg
that's not the case with the EXP 7i this
treadmill offers a lot of the same
techsavvy features as their higher end
models but at a discounted price there's
a lot to like about this treadmill so
let's get right to this
[Music]
review
what's up everybody it's Jake back in
the Barb and garage gym for today's
video I've got the Nordic Track exp 7i
treadmill in for review if you're new to
this whole process in this video today
we're going to talk about a lot but
specifically we're going to go over some
money talking about some pros and cons
some of the features this treadmill has
to offer and of course who should or
maybe should not make this purchase now
real quick before I do all that I got to
let you know we've reviewed a ton of
treadmills on barbin decom and we went
ahead and made a best list of all of our
top picks so if you want to check that
out all you to do is Google barbend best
treadmills that list is going to pull
right up for you you can find out for
yourself which ones we like the
best okay so as I said there's a lot to
like about this treadmill and I think
the first thing we got to talk about is
the price tag so the EXP 7i it's going
to run you right around 1,300 bucks
which is by far the cheapest treadmill
that Nordic Track has to offer but as I
mentioned you're still getting those
same modern conveniences as the higher
end models speaking of that you have a
7inch touchscreen monitor right there at
your fingertips it's going to Grant you
access to iFit if you don't know what
IIT is I mean definitely need to get on
board with that because there's over
16,000 different classes for you to join
and obviously you know there's plenty
that involve the treadmill there's also
strength training Yogo meditation
there's a whole lot that I'll detail
later on now during those IIT classes
with the treadmill you're going to
experience you automatic adjustments to
the incline and to the speed and
speaking of both of those factors with
the incline ranges from 0° you know flat
up to 12% with the speed you have 10
different miles per hour for you to work
with now I also really like how they
included a built-in tablet holder right
in front of that touchscreen monitor
this is really nice you know that way if
you just want to you know do a manual
workout and you want to stream your
favorite show or listen to a podcast or
whatever it is you have that right there
plus you can always just kind of keep
your phone you know on hand right there
in that Tabit hole which is just pretty
cool now the treadmill does fold that
deck does fold so it's going to be great
for anybody who's tight on space and the
wheels you know it makes it super easy
for you to move it around your personal
space I want to backtrack to the speed
settings though so you can always you
know press the buttons that are on
either side of the Monitor and you can
press the five for example it's going to
go to 5 miles per hour cool feature with
Nordic Track stuff though is that you
can actually double tap whatever button
it is stick with five double tap five
it's going to go to 5 and 1 half miles
per hour so I just think that's that's
pretty cool now you also have Bluetooth
capab abilities for a heart rate monitor
your headphones your phone or a
Bluetooth speaker so that's pretty cool
now all that being said there's still
some stuff that you definitely you know
be reminded of and first thing is going
to be actual incline and speed settings
so 12% incline that's pretty solid but
there's no decline settings a lot of
people like having that Decline and then
you 10 mph that's pretty good for you
know this quality treadmill in the price
range and everything but there's plenty
of other treadmills that have you know
mes per hour speed if you're somebody
who really likes to you know work in
those wind Sprints now to really get the
most out of this treadmill you are going
to have to pay an IIT membership I'm
going to expand on the different options
that are available but you're going to
at least have to pay 40 bucks a month
you know just to get the most out of
this treadmill so that could be a bummer
for some people another thing here is
that there are not any pulse sensors
built into that handlebar so for
somebody who wants to track your heart
rate you know at all times and get an
accurate reading of your calories that
are being burned then you if you don't
already have a rate monitor then you're
going to have to go and actually
purchase one Nord TR has one it's about
100 bucks it's not that bad but just
keep that in mind you're going to have
to go and do that there's also not a fan
built into the console on this treadmill
and if you're somebody who you know
really works up a sweat as you're
running you know that's probably not
going to be the most ideal thing in the
world for you speaking of running though
so the rollers on this treadmill are 1.9
in in diameter now if you don't really
understand what that is rollers play you
know a very important role
no pun intended in the performance of a
treadmill so the smaller they are the
faster they have to turn to keep up with
the motor to keep that belt turning so
you're somebody who's a longdistance
runner dedicated Sprinter you know all
those kind of things you're going to
want to Target a treadmill that has
larger size rollers I'd say anywhere
from 2.25 to 2 and2 Ines in diameter
just to you know really get the most
longevity out of your treadmill another
thing here is that the motor is a little
bit under siiz for the price tag I I
guess it's still okay but it's a 2.6 CHP
motor CHP is constant horsepower so it's
always going to perform at 2.6 but you
know you can find plenty of other
treadmills that have a stronger motor
and that could come into effect you know
once again with you know a longdistance
runner for example and then lastly here
the actual deck you know the running
surface is a little bit small so it's 20
in wide there's a lot of other ones that
are 20 in wide you can also get some 22
in wide ones so just you know just for
reference but it's 55 in Long there a
lot of treadmills that are 60 in long so
if you're somebody who has you know a
long stride then you're probably going
to want to Target one of those different
models okay so once again the Nordic
Track exp 7i treadmill it's going to run
you right around $1,300 well that's the
base price tag similar to the rest of
Nordic tracks equipment the final price
tag is going to be determined on some
variables first of all it's going to be
your choice of IIT subscription you can
either pay 40 bucks a month or you can
go after one of the three different
yearly options so that one- year plan is
going to run you around 400 bucks 700
bucks for the 2-year plan and about 900
bucks for that three-year plan obviously
that's you know going to increase the
original price tag by a significant
amount but you're also going to save a
good chunk of money in the long run just
for example that threeyear plan over
that course of time if you you pay $900
up front versus paying $40 a month
you're going to save about $500 so there
somebody you know who envisions himself
you know being locked into that IIT
membership it's probably going to be
worth that money you know in the grand
scheme of things now it comes with a
10-year warranty on the frame two years
on parts and one year on labor but if
you spend 300 bucks and go after that
extended warranty plan you'll get 5
years on Parts and four years on labor
another thing you can do is spend 450
bucks on the extended maintenance plan
now you're only going to get extra two
years on parts and labor but you will
have an annual 15-point checklist during
that time frame so somebody from Nordic
Track is going to come out and they're
going to basically just make sure that
your treadmill is performing at its
highest capacity another thing here you
can go after is White Glove assembly so
you know whenever you receive your
treadmill you can pick the room of
choice and you know whoever delivers it
for you will in fact you know assemble
it and make sure everything's
functioning properly for you which is
pretty cool now Nordic Track does offer
financing directly through them because
you know the highest this could be is
about 2700 bucks not everybody wants to
do that up front even if it's 1,300
bucks I get it not everybody wants to
spend that right up front so they offer
financing through them over a 39 month
span and a cool thing with their website
is that as you're selecting all your
variables and everything it's actually
going to update in real time and show
you your monthly payments you know over
that course of
[Music]
time and remember you know the main
selling point with this treadmill it's
the modern conveniences and specifically
you know IIT so take a quick second and
talk about those classes that are
available remember there's so many you
know I wish I could name all of them but
I can't it's physically impossible
there's last time I checked there's like
over 16,000 I mean there's and it's
growing they're constantly coming out
with new individual classes as well as
challenges so with those challenges
these can consist up to 30 different
individual workouts once you complete it
you're going to get a trophy go in your
trophies tab yay woohoo you see how see
how great you're doing and there's a
progression tab too so you can always
you know track your stats and kind of
just see your overall arching you know
Fitness level I guess you could say now
there's Studio classes where you know
you're kind of you know in that studio
setting you know virtually you know your
trainers in the studio setting but
there's also different options where you
can basically travel the world I mean
you can literally virtually travel the
world there's so many different to
choose from and actually you know this
isn't technically a class but there's a
Google Google Maps feature and this is
on all their equipment but you can pick
any city in the world and incline is
going to adjust automatically to the lay
of the land thanks to Google Maps and
you get the Google Map street street Cam
and that's just pretty cool now another
thing here is the companion app which I
think is a really useful tool so you can
track all your stats and your trophies
and you know look at your calendar and
workout history and all that but you
know let's say you want to do you know a
strength training class well with other
treadmills that Nordic Track offers that
monitor rotates 360° you can hop off on
the ground and and do all those classes
that way this one does not so actual
console is fixed and that monitor just
kind of rotates or tilts I guess you
could say a little bit so this is where
that companion app comes into handy you
can stream any workout you want from
your phone or your tablet and all of
your stats I mean it's the same profile
right so it's all going to you know go
straight onto the treadmill and vice
versa so that's just pretty cool too
[Music]
so with the EXP 7i you do have a steel
framework this treadmill weighs about
228 lbs and it has a 300 lb weight
capacity which is you know pretty
respectable now the deck does in fact
fold thanks to the Hydraulics it's super
easy I'm going to show you how to do
that in just a second super easy for you
to do and that's great you know it
creates more floor space for when you
need it plus there's a set of wheels
that's going to make it relatively easy
for you to you move the actual treadmill
around your personal space and one more
thing to remember is that you do in fact
have a 10-year warranty on the actual
framework which is pretty solid now that
7-in touchscreen monitor is going to
display you it's going to track your
speed incline setting and it's going to
estimate the amount of calories you've
burned and your actual heart rate but if
you purchase a heart rate monitor it's
going to have an accurate reading of
both of those variables you have two cup
holders and remember you do have that
built-in tablet holder as well which is
nice for people for people who like to
stream the favorite show movies or
whatever as they're you know doing their
cardio workouts remember you do have a
Max incline of 12% and a top speed of 10
mes hour and during you know your IIT
classes you have the luxury of having
automatic adjustments to both of those
variables which is pretty sweet but you
want to override that anytime you
definitely can there's buttons on either
side of the display it's going to you
know you press 5 miles hour for example
you go straight to five you press you
know 10% inclin going to go up to 10% or
you know you can use the arrows that are
underneath those numbers and kind of go
up you know and and smaller increments
which is pretty cool too all right so
just to Showcase really quick how easy
it is to fold this deck just lift up
right here on the back of the treadmill
look one hand the Hydraulics basically
takes care of the rest of it and then it
locks into place this is you know
perfect for anybody who's tight on space
but also just to create more floor space
in general now to fold it down all
you're going to do is put your foot
right here but really quick before I do
that I do want to mention you know your
roll one of your rollers is right here
remember this is 1.9 in in diameter and
you know so if you're a dedicated Runner
Sprinter longdistance Runner all that
you're probably going to want to Target
a treadmill that has you know bigger
rollers right here and the other one is
in the front of the treadmill I'll show
you in just a second all right now to
fold this down just put your foot right
here like the diagram says push it up
kind of unlocks it a little bit and then
you can let go and that hydraulic lift
system is just going to take care of
everything for you now the deck remember
it measures 55 in Long by 20 in wide so
it's a little bit narrow compared to you
know a lot of other treadmills just by 2
in though might not be that big of a a
deal for everybody but it is 5 in
shorter than whole lot of other
treadmills so if you have a long stride
you're a tall person whatever probably
going to want to Target you know a 60in
deck now that other roller as I was
mentioning is located right up here and
then your 2.6 CHP motor is hidden
underneath right here and
2.6 that's pretty average I guess you
know with a treadmill in this price
range but if you're somebody who wants a
beefier motor you know you're just going
to have to spend more money on that all
right now let's move further up right
here so obviously this is your console
this is fixed so it does not move at all
the actual monitor itself right here
does tilt a little bit it's not really
going to do much for you but if you want
or need to you definitely can I really
do like how they you included this you
know integrated tablet holder right here
it's kind of a rarity with you know
companies who have their own streaming
platform and everything so that's pretty
cool if you just want to watch your TV
show boom you can definitely do so all
right so go ahead and click tap to start
we're sitting here on the library right
now and as I mentioned you know there's
so many classes to choose from so this
is a fitness Foundation you know this is
a seven workouts right here six workouts
there's an intro to interval training
that's a beginner it's a 28 minute you
that's an individual you know one-off
class it's going to tell you you know
1.66 miles and it's approximately going
to burn about 28 calories so that's
pretty cool how it kind of displays that
information for you there's a lot of
other ones you know like I said this is
16 workout 161 12 just kind of goes on
and on 33 workouts there's a lot with
these challenges and everything road to
recovery there's so much going on you
got your trophy case down here on the
bottom right once you complete all those
you know you get your little trophy get
your little badge and just goes right in
there now you can click create right
here this is what I love to do take a
second to load right here it loves
taking me to Cape Town South Africa
first thing I feel like it does that
every single time but I just want to
show youall really quick we're going to
exit that go right back and let's see
where it takes us now Paris France so
it's pretty cool you can kind of it's
like roulette almost you know you can
just kind of press it and takes you
pretty much anywhere in the world uh and
if you go back to home right here ex it
again if it would let me exit again
there we go and you can keep scrolling
right here and it's going to have you
know the latest this is all where you
know the featured classes and anything
that's new and fresh kind of gets on
this home screen right here so that's
pretty cool too now do not have any
programmed classes but you can go to
manual start right here and this is a
pretty cool feature for anybody who
doesn't necessarily have the time to do
a full you know lengthy class or
anything and you just hop on for a few
minutes at a time and get your workout
in now go ahead and click end workout
right end warmup excuse me and I just
want to show you remember this is a
little bit of a weaker motor compared to
for the price range is fine but you know
like I said there's other ones that are
definitely stronger so we're going to
click 10 mil per
hour that's a pretty quick response time
for a motor like this it's pretty
quick it's relatively loud you know
we're at top speed now but it kind of is
what it is you know you get what you get
and then with this with the incline this
definitely does take a second quick 12
let's see let's drop down here and it
definitely does take a bit of a you know
couple
seconds that's just because you know
once again it's that motor that's what's
doing it now I'm not dogging this
treadmill by any means I like this
treadmill I think this is a great you
know budget purchase for anybody who
wants all these luxury features just
want to show you you know that it does
take a second
to Incline up like
that still going that's okay that's
okay yeah so right there we go now that
does allow your body to kind of adjust a
little bit and get used to the incline
so it's you know a gradual process but
you know some people don't really want
that some people want you know more of
an instant you know know reaction I
guess you could say response I guess I
should say with their treadmills so
that's something you should keep in mind
now go and and pop it back down it's
still going to take a second but after
you're done with your workout you know
you just end it really quick go ahead
and stop it it's going to save all your
workout stats and that's going to be
really cool you can track all your
progress and do all of that whether it
be from the companion app or directly
through here and that's just a great
thing too so I think the EXP 7i is a
great purchase for anybody who wants a
luxury treadmill without actually paying
that luxury price tag cuz this is
honestly pretty affordable 1,300 bucks
for what you're getting out of this I
think it's a pretty sweet deal and then
also anybody who wants a streaming
platform built into their treadmill this
is one of the better options you that
you're going to get specifically for the
price tag now on the flip side there are
some reasons why you might not want to
purchase this treadmill and really first
thing that comes to mind is if you're
you know a dedicated Runner remember
these rollers are 1.9 in so you're
probably going to want to Target you
know treadmill that has larger rollers
and then also you know there's some
variables you might be looking for that
this one might not necessarily have for
you remember Max incline 12% you can
find some other ones that are higher
plus if you want to sprinkle in some
decline you can definitely find that as
well and then if you're somebody who
wants you know to really hit your
Sprints and you want faster than 10 mil
per hour there's plenty of other options
that go up to 12 miles per hour then
lastly you know if you just want a basic
treadmill you know no frills you just
want you know a standard treadmill to
hop on maybe some programmed workouts
within it and just kind of burn some
extra calories you can definitely do so
and save some money in the
process that's all I got for y'all today
on the Nordic Track exp 7i this Nordic
track's budget friendly treadmill it's
not perfect but you know I still think
there's a lot of things that it does
really well thanks for hanging out with
me I hope this video was really helpful
and I was able to break down everything
you need to know about this treadmill I
say it all the time and I'm not going to
quit saying it keep your eyes posted for
my next video but for now head over to
barbin do.com cuz we have a full written
article about this treadmill that I
definitely think you should go and check
out all you got to do is search barbend
Nordic Track exp 7i treadmill review
it's going to pull right up for you you
can go over every single thing we talked
about here today I'll catch youall next
[Music]
time
he